A Finding Aid to the National Arts Club Records, 1898-1960, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Membership, circa 1900-1962; Series 4; Archival Resource Key
  - Membership Rosters, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4256)
    - Rosters, circa 1900; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4256, Frame 942-1054)
    - Rosters, circa 1900, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4257, Frame 4-28)
    - Rosters, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4257, Frame 30-285)
    - Rosters, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4257, Frame 287-474)
    - Rosters, 1932-1934; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4257, Frame 476-682)
    - Rosters, 1936-1938; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4257, Frame 684-876)
    - Rosters, 1947 (some pages out of order); Archival Resource Key (Reel 4257, Frame 878-1123)
    - Rosters, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4257, Frame 1125-1372)
    - Rosters, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4257, Frame 1374-1426)
    - Rosters, 1951-1952, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4258, Frame 4-118)
    - Rosters, 1951-1952, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4258, Frame 121-368)
    - Rosters, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4258, Frame 370-586)
    - Rosters, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4258, Frame 588-797)
    - Rosters, 1956-1962; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4258, Frame 799-1022)
    - Rosters, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4258, Frame 1024-1217)
    - Rosters, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4258, Frame 1219-1238)
    - Rosters, 1949-1950 (target incorrectly reads 1959); Archival Resource Key (Reel 4258, Frame 1239-1433)
    - Rosters, 1949-1950, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 4-69)
- Arts Realty Co., 1909-1913, 1945-1956, undated; Series 5; Archival Resource Key
  This small group of records is extant. For additional information relating to the Arts Realty Co. see Series 2.1: Officers' Correspondence, Mortgage Bonds.
  - List of Stockholders, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 73-76, 81)
  - Resolution of Board of Directors, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 77)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 78)
  - Stock Certificates, Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 79-80)
  - Correspondence regarding mortgage bonds, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 81-183)
  - Minutes of Stockholders' Meetings, 15 Gramercy Park, Inc., 1945-1956; Archival Resource Key; (1 volume) (Reel 4259, Frame 184-344)
- Miscellaneous, 1890-1961, undated; Series 6; Archival Resource Key
  This series includes various legal documents, material predating establishment of the National Arts Club, unpublished speeches delivered at the Club, information about clubhouses occupied, and histories of the organization.
  Letters predating the establishment of the club include copies of letters concerning French military equipment and de Kay to J.Q.A. Ward outlining plans for founding a society of sculptors. Speeches include addresses delivered at the Annual Thanksgiving Dinner by Walter S. Logan in 1905; at a dinner in honor of Spencer Trask in 1908; by the Ambassador of Indonesia in 1953; by President Talcott at a reception in honor of the art students of New York, undated; and "The Future of the Horse" by Charles de Kay, also undated. Records on clubhouses include the lease for 156 Fifth Ave. (first office of National Arts Club); lease for 37 West 34th St., and longitudinal section of alterations to NAC, 37 West 34th St. (first clubhouse); maps of Gramercy Park; floorplan of the Grille Room showing placement of tables; and a fact sheet and miscellaneous notes concerning the Tilden Mansion (present clubhouse).
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1898, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 350-367)
  - Constitution of the National Arts Club, 1900; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 368-379)
  - Letters Predating Establishment of the National Arts Club, 1890-1897; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 380-390)
  - Speeches (see also Series 8.1: National Arts Club Printed Matter, Speeches), 1905-1953; undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 391-460)
  - Biographical Notes on Gates Douglas Fahnestock (1853-1936) and Samuel J. Tilden (1814-1886), undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 466-473)
  - Library notes and lists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 466-473)
  - Facts and Figures concerning the National Arts Club, circa 1947; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 474-549)
    (includes lists of artwork missing from the permanent collection, governors with dates of election, and priviledged societies)
  - Histories of the National Arts Club, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 550-610)
  - Drawings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 611-620)
    (Old Dutch Grille; 7 drawings of costumes for Gramercy Park pageant by A. Garfield Learned)
  - Donations to Piano Purchase Fund, undated; Archival Resource Key; (on illuminated sheet) (Reel 4259, Frame 621-622)
  - Calendars of Events/Programs, Invitations (not printed), 1955/56-1956/57; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 623-629)
  - Clubhouses, 1898-1899, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 630-640)
  - Miscellaneous Legal Documents (relating to real estate), 1911-1930; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 641-671)
- Photographs, 1899-1957, undated; Series 7; Archival Resource Key
  Arrangement
  Missing Title
  7.1: People, undated
  7.2: Exhibitions, Gallery Installations and Works Exhibited, 1899-1957
  7.3: Works of Art, undated
  7.4: Building, undated
  7.5: Events, 1931-1956, undated
  7.6: Miscellaneous, undated
  7.7: Negatives, 1910-1921, undated
  7.8: Album, 1910-1921, undated
  7.9: Oversized, undated
  This series is organized into nine subseries.
  Photographs of individuals are filed alphabetically by category: Officer, Governors, and Life Members; Artists; and Others. Group photographs are categorized as identified and unidentified, and arranged in chronological order. Exhibition installation shots are arranged chronologically, and photos of works of art are alphabetized by name of artist. Interior and exterior views of the National Arts Club building are arranged in rough chronological order, as are pictures of events. An album contains: views of exhibition installations, 1910-1917, in chronological order, and a few portraits of prize recipients and artist members, 1917-1921. Oversize photos follow.
  - People, undated; 7.1; Archival Resource Key
    Photographs of officers, governors, and life members include: John C. Agar, Charles Coburn, Bird S. Coler, Shubael Cottle, E. Irving Couse, Gates D. Fahnestock, Oscar Fehrer, J. William Fosdick, John R. Gregg, Harold Howland, Chester Loomis, John Clude Oswald, George B. Post, F.W. Ruckstuhl, and Frank R. Towle. Photographs of artists include: H.R. Bacher, Hilda Belcher, Louis Betts, Isabel Bishop, George Elmer Browne, Gordon Grant, Daniel Greene, Mauno Oittinen, Leon Volkmar, and Harry Voorhees. Photographs of others include Alistair Cooke, David Nadien, Mrs. Leonard Tyson Scully, Mrs. Alfred Chappell, and Eleanor Wendell.
    - Officers, Governors, and Life Members, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 675-722)
    - Artists, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 724-754)
    - Others, Unidentified, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 755-789)
    - Groups, Unidentified and Identified, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 790-815)
  - Exhibitions, Gallery Installations and Works Exhibited, 1899-1957; 7.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Gold and Silver Exhibition, Oct. 1899; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 817-821)
    - Members' Exhibition, April 1908; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 822-828)
    - Art Students League Exhibition, May 1908; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 829-835)
    - Third Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 1908; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 836-840)
    - International Exhibition of Pictorial Photography, Feb. 3-20, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 841-844)
    - John W. Alexander Retrospective, March 1909; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 845-861)
    - Exhibition of the New York Society of Keramic Arts, April 1909; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 862-870)
    - Fourth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, Dec. 1910; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 871-881)
    - Walter Shirlaw Memorial Exhibition, March 8-April 5, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 882-886)
    - Group Exhibition: William R. Derrick, Gifford Beal, Reynolds Beal, and Frederick J. Waugh, April-May 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 887-897)
    - Exhibition of Color Schemes and Model Rooms in Miniature, Oct. 25-Nov. 4, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 898-902)
    - Sixth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 8-30, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 903-911)
    - Fifth Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, Dec. 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 912-914)
    - Otto Walter Beck Exhibition, Feb. 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 915-917)
    - Sculpture Exhibition, May 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 918-920)
    - Sixth Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, Dec. 4-28, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 921-922)
    - Applied Arts of Germany, March 12-31, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 924-926)
    - Seventh Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, Dec. 3-28, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 927-937)
    - Hungarian Peasant Art, March 11-29, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 938-943)
    - Annual Exhibition of Small Sculpture, May 6-31, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 944-958)
    - Members' Exhibition, June-Oct. 1915; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 959-961)
    - Loan Exhibition of Portraits of Academicians and Associates Selected from the Permanent Collection of the National Academy of Design, March 2-25, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 962-965)
    - Twentieth Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 1925; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 966-969)
    - Decorative Arts Exhibition, Dec. 1929; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 970-998)
    - Eighth Annual Exhibition by Living American Etchers, Dec. 3-26, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 999-1001)
    - Thirty-second Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, Nov. 1937; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1002-1004)
    - Exhibition of Indonesian Art, March 1953; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1005-1014)
    - Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition of Books of the Year, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1015-1018)
    - International Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture, June 1957; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1019-1025)
    - Arts and Crafts Exhibitions, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1026-1044)
    - Annual Exhibitions of Books of the Year, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1045-1052)
    - Ceramic Art Exhibition, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1053-1055)
    - Pottery Exhibition, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1056-1058)
    - Traveling Exhibition of Enlarged Photographs of Sculpture and Spring Exhibition of Small Sculpture by Members of the National Sculpture Society, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1059-1065)
    - Exhibition of Small Sculpture, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1066-1067)
    - Exhibition of Still Life and Flower Paintings in Oil, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1068-1070)
    - Unidentified Exhibitions, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1071-1107)
  - Works of Art, undated; 7.3; Archival Resource Key
    The photographs in this subseries are of works of art that were, presumably, exhibited at the National Arts Club or belong to the Club's permanent collection. Works of art pictured are by artists including Edmund John Archer, C.H. Barr, Alexander Franham, Charles W. Hawthorne, Anna Hyatt Huntington, Marianthe Karaberi, La Duble, Allen G. Newman, Mauno Oittinen, Jo Paddock, and Annabelle E. Williams.
    - Works of Art, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1108-1196)
  - Building, undated; 7.4; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains photographs of the exterior and the interior of the National Arts Club building.
    - Exterior, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1197-1210)
    - Interior, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1211-1227)
  - Event, 1931-1956, undated; 7.5; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains photographs of various National Arts Club events. For additional photographs in this category see Series 7.8: Album, and Series 7.9: Oversize, Mural Decorations in the Galleries (Mi Careme Festival)
    - New Year's Eve Carnival, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1230-1232)
    - Faith Baldwin speaking at the Thirty-second Annual Exhibition of Books of the Year, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1233-1235)
    - Wild West Costume Ball, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1236-1242)
    - Twenty-fifth Annual Exhibition and Members Dinner, Society of American Etchers, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1243-1246)
    - Charles Coburn and Boris Bogdanovitch at War Bond Auction, circa 1943; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1247-1249)
    - Ruth Renfrew and Florence Duryea with Greek dolls, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1250-1254)
    - Opening of the Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1255-1262)
    - Presentation of award to Huntington Hartford at Fifty-eighth Annual Exhibition, Dinner for Artist Members, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1263-1264)
    - Decorations by Junior Members for New Year's Eve Party, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1265-1271)
    - Demonstration at Old Mill Art School, Elizabethtown, N.Y., undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1272-1274)
    - Unidentified, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1275-1308)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 7.6; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains photographs of an unidentified house and of the National Arts Club medal of honor. For additional photographs in this category see Series 7.8: Album.
    - National Arts Club Medal of Honor, House, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4259, Frame 1309-1312)
  - Negatives, undated; 7.7; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains negatives that were not microfilmed.
    - Negatives, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel Unfilmed)
  - Album, 1910-1921, undated; 7.8; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries contains 1 disbound volume containing photographs of exhibition installations from 1910 to 1917 and photographs of people and events dating from 1917 to 1921.
    - Third Annual Exhibition of Advertising Art, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 6-8)
    - Fourth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 9-10, 12)
    - First Annual Exhibition of the Work of Artist Life Members, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 11, 13-14)
    - Exhibition of the New York Society of Keramic Arts, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 15-18)
    - Walter Shirlaw Memorial Exhibition, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 19-22)
    - Color Schemes and Model Rooms in Miniature, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 26-28)
    - Group Exhibition, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 23-25)
    - Fifth Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 32-34)
    - Sixth Annual Book Exhibition, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 29-31)
    - Otto Walter Beck, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 38-40)
    - Etchings of T. E. Hurley, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 41, 46-47)
    - Pictures of National Parks, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 42-44)
    - Emerson McMillan Collection, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 45, 48-52)
    - Members' Special Prize Exhibition, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 35-37)
    - Sculpture Exhibition, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 53-55)
    - Exhibition of Industrial Art (Art Dept. of the City High Schools), 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 56-58)
    - Annual Exhibition of the Society of Illustrators, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 59-61)
    - Sixth Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 62-64)
    - Works of Frederick W. Freer, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 68-70)
    - Members' Special Prize Exhibition, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 65-67)
    - Applied Arts of Germany, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 71-73)
    - Group Exhibition, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 74-76)
    - Sculpture Exhibition, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 77-79)
    - Annual Arts and Crafts Exhibition, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 80-82)
    - Painter Members Exhibition, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 83-86)
    - Hungarian Peasant Art, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 87-90)
    - Group of Western Painters, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 91-93)
    - Sculpture, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 94-97)
    - Eighth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 98-101)
    - Painter Members Exhibition, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 102-104)
    - Exhibition of the American Water Color Society, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 105-109)
    - Ninth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 110)
    - Painter Members Exhibition, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 111-112)
    - National Academy of Design Loan Exhibition of Portraits, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 115-116)
    - Exhibition of American Water Color Society, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 113-114)
    - Members' Annual Exhibition, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 117-118)
    - Exhibition of Books of the Year, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 119-120)
    - Twelfth Annual Exhibition of Arts and Crafts, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 123-125)
    - Medals, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 120-121)
    - Portrait of Mme. Signe Lund, winner of prize for best patriotic music, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 122)
    - Portrait of Daniel Henderson, winner of prize for best patriotic music, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 122)
    - F. Luis Mora making part of a frieze for New Year's Eve Carnival, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 126)
    - Group of artists working on frieze, [1920?]; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 129-130)
    - Ernest L. Ipsen making poster for New Year's Eve Carnival, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 126)
    - Group portraits of members attending New Year's Eve Carnival, 1920/21; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 127-134)
    - Edwin Booth Memorial, Gramercy Park, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 135)
  - Oversize, undated; 7.9; Archival Resource Key
    For additional photographs relating to mural collections in the galleries see Series 7.8: Album.
    - Mural Decorations in the Galleries (Mi Careme Festival), undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 136-138)
- Printed Matter, 1893-1960, undated; Series 8; Archival Resource Key
  Printed matter is organized into two subseries:
  8.1: National Arts Club Printed Matter, circa 1900-1960, undated
  8.2: Non-National Arts Club Printed Matter, 1893-1959, undated
  Series 8.1 is arranged by record type. Series 8.2 is organized by subject, with the exception of clippings which are arranged chronologically.
  - National Arts Club Printed Matter, circa 1900-1960, undated; 8.1; Archival Resource Key
    Yearbooks include the constitution, by-laws, house rules; lists of members, officers, and committees; and lists of exhibitions and lectures presented. The books are illustrated with pictures of the clubhouse, exhibitions, and events. Bulletins contain calendars of events, lists of newly elected members, and news of members. The 1909, 1914, and 1939-1940 issues include pictures of exhibition installations, the clubhouse interior including the restaurant and men's grill, social events, and prizewinning art work. Brochures contain general information for guests and prospective members. Many are illustrated with views of the building, exhibitions, and social events. Of particular interest is the 1906 brochure which contains a description of the new clubhouse with floorplans.
    The subseries also contains announcements, invitations, tickets, entry blanks, and artist prospectuses; and programs relating to concerts, social activities, meetings of the Men's Open Table, and anniversary celebrations. Speeches include "Tribute to William Winter," 1909; "Social Art, an Address Delivered to The Open Table by F.W. Ruckstuhl," 1915; and "The Tilden Mansion, Home of the National Arts Club," by Charles Rollinson Lamb, 1932. Miscellaneous publications include "Forty Seven Facsimile Drawings by American Artists," by the American Artists' War Emergency Fund, 1918; "What Europe Thinks of American Art, Eminent Opinions Compiled by Henry Rankin Poore, A.N.A.," circa 1930; and printed pictures (reproductions of photographs).
    - Constitution, By-laws, and House Rules, 1940-1959, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 156-203)
    - Yearbooks, 1901-1905/06; 1911-1915/16;1917/18-1921/22; 1923/24; 1930/31; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 204-790)
    - Membership Lists (see also Series 4: Membership; Series 8.1: National Arts Club Printed Matter, Yearbooks; and Series 8/2: Non-National Arts Club Printed Matter, Club Members of New York), circa 1900-1951; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 791-975)
    - Bulletin [title varies slightly], 1907-1901; 1914; 1919-1920; 1924; 1928-1958; 1960; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4260, Frame 976-1138)
    - Bulletin, 1907-1901; 1914; 1919-1920; 1924; 1928-1958; 1960, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4261, Frame 7-997)
    - Brochures, 1898-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4261, Frame 998-1082)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1902-1955/56; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4261, Frame 1083-1110)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1902-1955/56, cont.; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 8-44)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Related Printed Matter (see also Appendix A), 1900-1960, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 85-321)
    - Events (see also Series 2.8: Men's Open Table), 1912-1960, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 322-431)
    - Speeches (see also Series 6: Miscellaneous, Speeches), 1909-1932; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 45-84)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1918-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Reel 4262, Frame 432-556)
  - Non-National Arts Club Printed Matter, 1893-1959, undated; 8.2; Archival Resource Key
    Volume 8 of Club Members of New York in this subseries contains a list of club members. Additional lists can be found in Series 8.1: National Arts Club Printed Matter, Membership Lists and Yearbooks; and Series 4: Membership. Printed matter concerning other art organizations includes a general brochure of the Artist-Artisan Institute, undated, and extracts from speeches delivered at the initial meeting of the National Commission to Advance American Art, 1933. The records relating to Gramercy Park include a copy of "The Gramercy Glide," a song and dance dedicated to the National Arts Club.